Guide to the Records of the Leo Baeck Institute London undated, 1907-2008 (bulk 1956-2000) AR 6682
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series IV: Printed Material, undated, 1923-2004; bulk 1955-1975; 2.2 linear feet.
  - Subseries 3: Subject files, undated, 1923-1995; bulk 1956-1972; 1.3 linear feet.
    This subseries consists of subject-based clippings collections created by LBI London. All the files contain primarily clippings, but also include brochures and off-prints. A wide range of publications is represented. Many clippings come from mainstream European (primarily German and English) newspapers and scholarly journals. The American press, as well as the worldwide Jewish press, is also well-represented.
    The "Individual" subject files form a collection of clippings about individuals broadly relevant to the study of German Jews.
    "Subject File I" and "Subject File II" are two separate clippings files on subjects of general Jewish and German-Jewish interest, such as anti-Semitism, the Nuremberg trials, and individual Jewish communities. It is unclear why two separate subject files were maintained, but the second file appears to have been created at a slightly later date, as the clippings range from 1963 to 1974.
    A few clippings files on specific topics are also found here.
    The integrity of each subject file was maintained. Within the subject file, the clippings are arranged in alphabetical order by subject. Some folders contain subject lists.
    - Individual File, Abt - Aviad-Wolfsberg, 1952-1988 (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Individual File, Baeck - Birnbaum, 1923-1986 (Box 22, Folder 51)
      Some copies
    - Individual File, Bischheim - Buber, 1957-1983 (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - Individual File, Buerger-Prinz - Eyck, 1959-1972 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Individual File, Feuchtwanger - Gold, 1957-1973 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Individual File, Goldmann - Heilbrunn, 1954-1971 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Individual File, Heine - Hirschberg, 1958-1971 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Individual File, Hirst - Kahn, 1958-1972 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Individual File, Karo - Langer, 1958-1994 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Individual File, Langfus - Marcus, 1957-1980 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Individual File, Marcuse - Oppenheimer, 1958-1972 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Individual File, Ostwald - Rosenthal, 1958-1975 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Individual File, Rosenzweig - Schoenberg, 1956-1971 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Individual File, Schoeps - Szold, 1931; 1953-1974 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Individual File, Sonnemann - Steinschneider, 1953-1973 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Individual File, Tau - Weber, 1958-1971 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Individual File, Weichmann - Wolfskehl, 1954-1972 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Individual File, Wormann - Zweig, 1958-1971 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Subject File 1, A-F, Undated, 1936, 1957-1965 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Subject File 1, G-M, Undated, 1957-1965 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Subject File 1, N-Z, Undated, 1956-1964 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Subject File 2, A-H, 1963-1974 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Subject File 2, J-N, 1964-1972 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Subject File 2, O-Z, 1964-1973 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Centralverein, 1924-1984 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      Copies
    - "Die deutschen Juden und der Liberalismus" conference, Koenigswinter, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - "Jews in Nazi Germany" conference, Berlin, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Resistance, 1970-1995 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Series V: Collected Materials, undated, 1907-2008; 0.5 linear feet.
  This small but wide-ranging series contains archival materials collected by or donated to LBI London. The context and provenance of many of these items is unclear, but it appears that many were unsolicited donations. The series include photographs, essays, clippings, letters, and off-prints about German-Jewish topics from before World War One through the late 2000s. The fact that these historical documents were and continue to be collected and preserved provides evidence of an ongoing impulse to document German-Jewish history.
  - Alexander Granach und das jiddische Theater des Ostens (poster), 1971 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - American Federation of Jews from Central Europe, "Information Bulletin", 1955 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Antisemitism in Germany (essays), 1950s? (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - "Antisemitismus und die Deutsche Geschichte" bibliography, 1950s? (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Der Archivar, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Bach, "Isaac Bernays", 1941 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Ben Shemen youth village, Undated, 1916-1937 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Beranek, "Das Rätsel des Regensburger Brückenmännchens", 1961 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - "Bericht aus der oeffentlichen Sitzung der Representanten-Versammlung der juedischen Gemeinde in Berlin betreffend Interpellation ueber die Angelegenheit des Predigers Dr. Emil Cohn", 1907 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Berliner, Cora (photograph), Undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Britschgi-Schimmer letter to Weltsch re Krojanker, 1932 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Boschwitz, Julius Wellhausen: Motive un Massstaebe seiner Geschichtsschreibung (dissertation), 1938 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    Copy
  - Burckhardt, Antisemitimus in Deutschland, Undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Clippings and printed material collected by Peter Brod, 1956, 1991-2008 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Collin, Once Upon Four Decades, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Dreyfus, "Hebrew Cemetery No. 1 of Galveston", 1965 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Evian conference, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Freier, Recha "Let the Children Come" (excerpts), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Heilbronner Vortraege, Heft 21, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Institute for Sociology of the Arts (bibliography), 1969 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Die Judensteine aus St. Marien in Parchim/Mecklenburg, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Kahn, Ludwig. Printed material about German-Jewish history, 1957-1963 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Kunoth, Report on difficulties at University of Bonn, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Leib, Ascent into the Abyss, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Lipschitz, Joachcim. Gedaechtnisfeier, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Mombert, Bevoelkerungslehre und Bevoelkerungsstatistik, 1919-1921 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    In German shorthand
  - Palestinian flyers from University of Hamburg, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Photographs of Florence and Athens, Undated (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Pinthus, "Die Wohnungsnot der Grosstadtjuden", 1929 (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Prayer calendar, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 35)
    Hungarian and Hebrew
  - "Pruefung, ob durch die Personalpolitik Misstaende im Auswaertigen Dienst eingetreten sind (Dr. Brill)", 1952 (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - Rede von Dr. Helfferich in der Universitaet Berlin, 1919 (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Reichstierschutzbund, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Remarks on Rilke, undated (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - Restitution materials, 1957-1961 (Box 24, Folder 40)
  - Die Rolle der Juden und der Judenfrage ... (research proposal), Undated (Box 24, Folder 41)
  - Rose, "Als Moses Kaz seine Stadt vor Napoleon rettete", 1999 (Box 24, Folder 42)
  - Rundverfuegung 90/41, Mitarbeiterverzeichnis, 1941 (Box 24, Folder 43)
  - Uebersicht zur Lehre der Wissenschaft vom Judentum, 1969-1971 (Box 24, Folder 44)
  - Unpublished manuscripts, Undated, 1954-1959 (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - Various, Undated, 1932-1988 (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - Weltsch clippings, reviews, notes, Undated, 1925-1944 (Box 24, Folder 47)
    Very fragile
  - Wiener Corps Briefe, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 48)
  - World Jewish Congress, "Jewish Cultural Affairs Vol XI", 1960 (Box 24, Folder 49)